Mss.Ms.Coll.115
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Eliza Middleton Kane Cope, 1884-1950; Eliza Middleton Kane Cope (1863-1952), of Germantown, Pennsylvania, was the daughter of Robert Patterson Kane and Elizabeth Francis Fisher Kane and wife of architect Walter Cope. Though primarily personal in nature, this collection of letters reflec
  Addams, Jane, 1860-1935; American League to Abolish Capital Punishment.; Cadwalader, Sophia Francis; Cain family.; Collegiate Anti-Militarism League.; Cope & Stewardson; Cope, Anne Francis, 1900-1982; Cope, Eliza Middleton Kane, 1863-1952; Cope, Elizabeth Frances, 1898-1977; Cope, Elizabeth Waln; Cope, Oliver, 1902-1994; Cope, Thomas Pim, 1897-1977; Cope, Walter, 1860-1902; Coxe, Sophia; Fisher, Eliza Middleton; Kane, Elizabeth Francis Fisher; Kane, Florence Bayard, 1868-1943; Kane, Francis Fisher, 1866-1955; Kane, Robert Patterson, 1827-1906; Workers' Defense League.; Germantown (Philadelphia, Pa.) -- Social life and customs.; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Social conditions.; Prison reformers -- United States.; Social reformers -- United States.
  - A, 1891-1943
  - Addams, Jane, 1921
  - Albury House, Guildford, 1888-1889
  - Alderson, Eleanor, 1896, 1902
  - Alma, 1927-1937
  - Alston, Ann, 1920-1921
  - American Child, 1943
  - American Guild of Organists, 1909
    New England Chapter.
  - American Institute of Architects, 1902
  - American League to abolish Capital Punishment, 1934
  - Aub, Clara, 1925
  - Aub, Joseph and Elizabeth (Cope), 1928-1943
  - Avery, Frederick Burt (Mrs.), 1937-1938
  - B, 1888-1948
  - Bach Choir, 1933-1934
  - Bacon, Francis H., 1902-1937
  - Baker, Eleanor, 1890-1892
  - Balch, Emily Greene, 1934-1949
  - Baldwin, Roger, 1920-1921
  - Banys, Mary, Undated
  - Barton, Ellen D., 1889-1896
  - Bell, Catherine M.E., 1902-1945, Undated
  - Bessie, 1920
  - Beylard, Mary, 1889-1893
  - Blake, Olivia M., 1896, Undated
  - Bliss, Eleanor, 1920-1921
  - Bohlen, Ingrid K., 1923 March 10
  - Brown, Fannie, 1917, 1922
  - Brown, Harriet, 1921-1923, 1933-1934
  - Brown, Mary Waln Wister, 1887
  - Bureau for Colored Children, 1945
  - Burson, Carolina P., 1905
  - C, 1887-1944
  - Cadwalader, John, 1910-1922
  - Cadwalader, Margaret, Undated
  - Cadwalader, Mary Helen, 1919
  - Cadwalader, Sophia #1, 1888-1891
  - Cadwalader, Sophia #2, 1905-1937
  - Cadwalader, Sophia #3, Undated
  - Charlotte, 1944
  - Chester, Mary Roberts, Undated
  - Cheston, Anne Morris, Undated
  - Cheston, Sally, Undated
  - Chew, Anne, 1889-1891
  - Chew, Mary, 1902-1929
  - Christenson, Edith, 1930
  - Civil Rights Congress, 1948
  - Cleghorn, Sarah N. (Sally), 1920-1950
  - Clifton, Sarah N., 1919 December 30
  - Collegiate Anti-Militarism League, 1917
  - Conover, Cornelia F. (Mrs. Richard), 1897-1933
  - Conscientious objectors, 1918
    Pamphlets of groups promoting the release from prison of conscientious objectors to World War I.
  - Consumers' League of Delaware, 1919 March 6
    Addressed to Mrs. Eliza Kent [sic] Kane Cope, in response to her comments in the Philadelphia Ledger of February 28, 1919, "Radical Movement, Mrs. Cope's Topic", regarding the organization, Young Democracy.
  - Cope, Alice (Mrs. Oliver), 1932-1937, undated
    Daughter-in-law.
  - Cope and Stewardson, 1902 November 5
    Condolence letter from staff of Walter Cope's architect firm upon his death.
  - Cope, Anna S., 1902
  - Cope, Anne Francis (Nancy) #1, 1909-1922
    Daughter. Married Thomas Pierrepont Hazard.
  - Cope, Anne Francis (Nancy) #2, 1923-1949
  - Cope, Anne Francis (Nancy) #3, Undated
  - Cope, Betty (Mrs. Thomas P.), 1931-1950, undated
  - Cope, Clementina, 1902 November 4
  - Cope, Eliza Middleton Kane, 1917-1919, undated
  - Cope, Elizabeth #1, 1912-1921
    Daughter. Married Joseph Aub.
  - Cope, Elizabeth #2, 1922
  - Cope, Elizabeth #3, 1923-1924
  - Cope, Elizabeth #4, 1927-1945
  - Cope, Elizabeth #5, Undated
  - Cope, Elizabeth S., 1902, 1922
  - Cope, Elizabeth Waln #1, 1892-1895
    Mother-in-law.
  - Cope, Elizabeth Waln #2, 1896-1901, undated
  - Cope, F. Hazen, Undated
  - Cope Family, 1943, undated
    Grandchildren.
  - Cope, Francis R., 1903 April 30
  - Cope, Henry, 1893 April 20
  - Cope, Margaret, 1903-1905
    Sister-in-law.
  - Cope, Oliver #1, 1918-1921
    Son. Wife Alice.
  - Cope, Oliver #2, 1922-1923
  - Cope, Oliver #3, 1924-1948
  - Cope, Oliver #4, Undated
  - Cope, Thomas P., 1893, 1898
    Father-in-law.
  - Cope, Thomas P., 1922, 1937
    Cousin.
  - Cope, Thomas P. #1, 1906-1920
    Son. Wife Betty.
  - Cope, Thomas P. #2, 1921
  - Cope, Thomas P. #3, 1922-1923
  - Cope, Thomas P. #4, 1924-1953
  - Cope, Thomas P. #5, Undated
  - Cope, Walter #1, 1893-1902
  - Cope, Walter #2, Undated
  - Cope, Walter Atlee, 1918 November 17
  - Coxe, Eckley B., 1891 May 11
  - Coxe, Edmund J.D., Undated
  - Coxe, Maria M., 1893, 1903, undated
  - Coxe, Polly, Undated
  - Coxe, Sophia #1, 1890-1909
    Sister of Elizabeth Francis Kane (E.M.C.'s Mother).
  - Coxe, Sophia #2, 1910-1919
  - Coxe, Sophia #3, 1920-1925
  - Coxe, Sophia #4, Undated
  - Coxe, Sophia (Mrs. Eckley), 1900-1933, undated
    Letters from the Cope family, Walter, Eliza, and their four children. Includes one from Oliver Cope describing his medical work in 1925 Peking. Also, one from Francis Fisher Kane decribing his drive against tuberculosis while in Vienna.
  - Crawford, Isabella A., 1911
  - D, 1886-1948
  - D., A.H., 1890-1891, undated
  - Day, Anna B., 1943
  - Day, Frank Miles, 1902-1903
  - Dillingham, E.C., Undated
  - Dillingham, W.H., Undated
  - Dos Passos, John R., 1918
  - Dupont, Jean Kane Foulke (Mrs. E. Paul), 1918-1945
  - E, 1889-1937
  - Elliott, Huger, 1890 March 2
  - Emlen, Arthur, 1892 September 10
  - Emlen, Eleanor C., 1892-1905
  - Erla, 1926-1933, undated
  - Esther, 1922-1926, undated
    Niece.
  - Evans, R.C., 1902
  - Eyre, Louise, 1940
  - F, 1890-1947
  - Farnum, J. Edward, 1886
  - Farnum, Paul, 1887-1889
  - Fawcett, James and Clara, 1921
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Undated
  - Fisher, Eliza Middleton, 1884-1891, undated
    Grandmother.
  - Fisher, George H. and Mrs., 1891, 1927
  - Fisher, Henry M., 1922-1929
  - Fisher, James Logan, 1902
  - Fisher, M. Lindley, Undated
  - Fisher, Margaret H., 1922
  - Fitzhugh, Cornelia, 1889-1937, undated
  - Fletcher, Ethel, 1918 January 11
  - Foulke, Jean Kane, 1888-1901
  - Fox, Emily R. #1, 1880-1922
  - Fox, Emily R. #2, Undated
  - Fox, J.M., 1880-1891, undated
  - Fox, Mary R., Undated
  - Francis, Elizabeth, Undated
  - Francis, Henry Sayles, 1921-1922
  - Fullen, C.G., Undated
  - Funiefs, George Wood, Undated
  - Furness, Oliver Kent, 1919 February 28
    Addressed to Mrs. Eliza Kent [sic] Kane Cope, in response to her comments in the Philadelphia Ledger of February 28, 1919, "Radical Movement, Mrs. Cope's Topic."
  - G, 1902-1944
    Sympathy cards.
  - Garrison, Mildred, 1918
  - Gilman, Elizabeth, 1938 March
  - Goddard, Margaret H., Undated
  - Goepp, Philip H., 1891-1935
  - H, 1888-1944
  - Haines, Ella, 1925-1944
  - Hale, Nathan, 1918-1921
  - Hale, Rose Perkins, Undated
  - Hale, Thomas Shaw, 1918
  - Hallinan, Charles T., 1917 December 5
  - Hamilton, Alice, 1932-1933
  - Hapgood, Mary Donovan, 1930
  - Harrison, Carol R.S., 1939
  - Harvard College, 1920
  - Hays, William C., 1902
  - Hayward, E.M., 1890 February 7
  - Hazard, Mary P.B., 1922-1933
  - Hazard, Thomas Pierrepont, 1922-1949
    Signs his name Pierre. Son -in-law. Husband of Anne F. (Nancy) Cope.
  - Hazard, Walter Mrs. (Nelly), 1888-1925, undated
  - Helen, undated
    Aunt
  - Helen, 1922-1923
    Cousin
  - Hoffman, Elizabeth, 1891
  - Howarth, Anne E., 1891
    Letterhead: Children's Country Week Association.
  - Huger, Margaret C., 1886-1887
  - Hunt, Alice Riggs, 1925
  - I, 1892-1937
  - Introduction and Advice, 1911-1920
  - J, 1885-1943
  - Jamieson, Effie and Janiest, 1912, 1918, undated
  - Jandrier, Jeanne, 1891-1932
  - January, Derick A., 1918-1922
  - January, Josephine, 1904-1933, undated
  - Johns, Frank, 1891 March 26
  - K, 1891-1947
  - Kane, E.D., 1887-1906
    Aunt Bess.
  - Kane, Elizabeth, Undated
  - Kane, Elizabeth Francis Fisher, 1888-1918, undated
  - Kane, Evan O'Neill, 1927-1933
  - Kane, Florence Bayard #1, 1887-1900
  - Kane, Florence Bayard #2, 1901-1911
  - Kane, Florence Bayard #3, 1912-1917
  - Kane, Florence Bayard #4, 1918-1920
  - Kane, Florence Bayard #5, 1921-1924
  - Kane, Florence Bayard #6, 1927-1942, undated
  - Kane, Francis Fisher #1, 1888-1893
    Brother.
  - Kane, Francis Fisher #2, 1894-1908
    Details brother's trip abroad.
  - Kane, Francis Fisher #3, 1917-1923
  - Kane, Francis Fisher #4, 1927-1943, undated
  - Kane, Harriet A., 1886-1891
  - Kane, Jean Duval Leiper, 1886, undated
  - Kane, Robert Patterson #1, 1881-1887
    Father.
  - Kane, Robert Patterson #2, 1888
  - Kane, Robert Patterson #3, 1889-1903
  - Kane, Robert Patterson #4, Undated
  - Kane, Sarah, 1922
  - Kane, Thomas P., 1922
  - Kane, Thomas S., 1887
  - L, 1891-1943
  - LaFollette, Belle C., 1921-1925
  - Lambert, John, Jr., 1889-1902, undated
  - Lansdale, Maria, 1891-1902
  - Lavalle, Rosita, 1891
  - Leeds, Anne Webb, 1902-1925, undated
  - Leuba, Berthe A., 1902, 1908
  - Leuba, J.H., 1903, 1918
  - Levy, Candice, 1881
  - Lewis, Caroline, Undated
  - Lewis, Shippen, 1922, 1948
  - M, 1891-1948
  - MacLarty, Flora, 1933, 1946
  - McCall, Maria, 1897, undated
  - McCullough, Edmund, 1889
  - McFadden, J. Frank, 1902
  - Marbury, William, 1922, 1935
  - Margaret, 1898, undated
  - Marquand, Eleanor, 1946
  - Martill, Mary, 1889
  - Middleton, Alicia H., 1921
  - Middleton, E., 1891-1928, undated
  - Middleton, Maria, 1902
  - Miscellaneous, 1891-1955
  - Mitchell, Weir, 1897, undated
  - Molitos, John B., 1902, undated
  - Morton, Mary W.W., 1888, 1902, undated
  - Moss, Molly, 1885-1911, undated
  - N, 1893-1949
  - National Woman's Peace Party, 1917
  - Nearing, Scott and Nellie, 1917, 1922, undated
  - Newsclippings, 1921, 1928, 1932, undated
  - Noland, Mary E., 1893-1897
  - Noland, William C., 1891-1922
  - O, 1897-1935
  - Oliver, Emily, 1917-1921, 1943
  - P, 1897-1939
  - Page, Ethel, 1897
  - Paget, Edith, 1937-1948
  - Parrish, Helen, Undated
  - Paul, J. Rodman, 1889-1891
  - Pearson, Mabel H., 1926-1928
  - Penniman, Josiah H., 1921
    Requesting admission of women to the School of Architecture at the University of Pennsylvania.
  - Pennsylvania Committee for Total Disarmament, 1930-1934
  - Pianelly, Norma, 1888-1919
  - Picot, Adele, 1889-1928
  - Postcards, 1906-1945, undated
  - Purves, Austin and Dale, 1920-1922
  - Quigley, Edward, 1930 December 17
  - R, 1893-1947
  - R., A.S. (Doria), 1933-1940
  - R., E.M., 1902
  - Radcliffe-Whitehead, Byrd, 1889-1929
  - Ratcliffe, Katie, 1919-1948
  - Ratcliffe, S.K., 1917-1943, undated
  - Read, Susan C., 1891, undated
  - Reid, Edith, 1890-1937, undated
  - Rhein, Elizabeth Kane, 1920-1926
  - Riesz, Helene, 1926-1932
  - Robins, Mary Ellis, 1900-1922
  - Rutenberg, Henry R., 1905 December 26
  - Rutledge, Alice, 1886-1890, undated
  - Rutledge, Benjamin H., Jr., 1890-1892
  - Rutledge, Oliver M., Jr., 1887-1891
  - S, 1889-1947
  - Savage, Charles Chauncey Jr., 1922
  - Schinner, Grace M., 1902-1928
  - Schuchardt, William H., 1902, 1922, 1938
  - Semple, Helen, 1913-1936, undated
    Contains reports of conditions of prisons in counties throughout Pennsylvania.
  - Sinith, Florence, 1895-1897
  - Smith, Alexander Mackay, 1921
  - Smith, Anna Wharton, 1891-1898, undated
  - Smith, Catherine C., Undated
  - Smith, Esther F.W., 1891-1893, undated
  - Smith, Esther Morton, 1891, 1937, undated
  - Smith, Mabel W., 1921-1922
  - Smith, William Wharton, 1891-1892, undated
  - Smolinhomker, Sophie, 1926, 1934
  - Stayton, L.T., 1897, 1902
  - Stewardson, Edmund A., 1889-1891, undated
  - Stewardson, Evelyn L., 1891, undated
  - Stewardson, John, Undated
  - Stewardson, Mary, Undated
  - Stokes, Ellen W., 1922
  - Stokes, May Margaret, Undated
  - Susy, 1887-1902
  - T, 1891-1947
  - Tall, I.R.M., 1888-1890, undated
  - Taylor, Irmgard, 1933-1946
  - Thayer, William S., 1920
  - Thomas, M. Carey, 1902
  - Thomson, M.I., 1920-1940, undated
  - Trowbridge, Robertson, 1922-1937
  - Tyler, Margaret, 1921
  - Unidentified #1, 1885-1936
    Primarily family members.
  - Unidentified #2, Undated
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1902
  - V, 1922, 1937, undated
  - W, 1891-1948
  - Welsh, Herbert, 1902
  - Wharton, K.J., 1922
  - Wharton, L.D., 1903
  - Wharton, Susan P., 1888, 1922
  - Whitmore, Mary, 1889, undated
  - Wickersham, M. Ella, 1923-1924, 1943
  - Winsor, Ellen, 1921-1935, undated
  - Winsor, Mary
  - Wistar, E.F., 1891-1898, undated
  - Wister, M.E., Undated
  - Wister, Mary Channing (Mrs. Owen, Jr.), 1902-1918, undated
  - Wister, Owen, 1920-1925
  - Wister, William Rotch (Mrs.), Undated
  - Witherspoon Hall, 1909-1910
  - Woman's reformatory, 1917 January 24
  - Wood, Anna Wharton, 1902, 1925
  - Woodward, Katharine F., 1928, undated
  - Worker's Defense Union, 1921
  - Wyer, Constance M.I., 1915-1916
  - Wyer, Florence, 1918-1932, undated
  - Y, 1932, undated
  - Yannall, Charlton, 1923
  - Yeatman, Pope, 1921-1922
  - Z, 1918-1919
- Series VII. Walter Cope, 1868-1902; Walter Cope was the distinguished architect whose firm developed the collegiate gothic stlye for various campus buildings. This small collection of letters, notebooks and receipts reflect some of his work, his personal correspondence, and his travels abroad. Letters of his participation in the T Square Club and at the University of Pennsylvania are also presented. Of note, a handwritten letter from the artist Maxfield Parrish.
  Walter Cope was born in Philadelphia, October 20, 1860, to Thomas P. Cope and Elizabeth Waln Stokes Cope. After graduating from Germantown Friends School, he attended the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts. He then studied abroad and upon his return in 1885 formed a partnership with John Stewardson. The architectural firm of Cope and Stewardson was best known for its academic and campus design called the collegiate gothic style. Between 1886-1904, this firm made additions to the campuses of Bryn Mawr College, Princeton University, University of Pennsylvania, and Washington University in St. Louis. Cope was also a professor of architecture at the University of Pennsylvania from 1892-1902 and a founding member of the T-Square Club. He died suddenly after suffering a stroke in 1902. He was survived by his wife, Eliza Middleton Kane Cope and four children: Thomas, Elizabeth, Anne and Oliver.
  American Institute of Architects. Philadelphia Chapter.; Cope & Stewardson; Cope, Thomas Pim, 1768-1854; Cope, Walter, 1860-1902; Laird, Warren Powers, 1861-1948; Parrish, Maxfield, 1870-1948; T Square Club. (Philadelphia, Pa.).; University of Pennsylvania. Dept. of Architecture.; Architects.
  - American Institute of Architects, Philadelphia chapter, undated
  - Bacon, Francis H., 1897-1898
  - Baker, Eleanor D., 1897
  - Bles, A., undated
  - Borie, J.J., 1892
  - Brown, D.J., 1900
  - Cadbury, Rebecca W., undated
  - Calling cards, undated
  - Cope, Alban, 1880
    Brother
  - Cope, Anna B., 1874
  - Cope, Elizabeth Waln, 1885-1895
  - Cope, Eliza Middleton Kane, 1901
    Wife.
  - Cope, John S., 1895
  - Cope, Margaret, 1882, 1891
    Sister.
  - Cope, Mary, 1884
  - Cope, Thomas P. to Walter Cope, 1889, 1893
    Father to Son.
  - Cope, Walter-Found in...pocket on morning after he died, 1902
  - Cope, Walter-List for wedding announcements, undated
  - Cope, Walter-Notebook, London trip, undated
  - Cope, Walter-Passport, 1895
  - Cope, Walter-Receipts and notes, 1884
  - Cope, Walter-Receipts and notes, 1895
  - Cope, Walter-Receipts, 1888, 1891
  - Cope, Walter--Speech, 1902
  - Cope, Walter to Thomas P. Cope #1, 1884
    Son to Father. Pertaining to his architectural studies abroad.
  - Cope, Walter to Thomas P. Cope #2, 1885
  - Corse, F.W., 1881, 1897
  - Costelloe, Marie, 1886
  - Coxe, Sophia, 1897
  - Emlen, Eleanor C., 1884
  - Evans, J., 1891
  - Fowler, T., 1892
  - Garrett, Elizabeth W., 1900
  - Hacker, Elizabeth D., 1891
  - Hutton, Addison, 1902
  - Hutton, Finley, 1892
  - Ismay Imrie and Company, 1885
  - Jarrell, Ann, 1902
  - Jesse, R.H., 1902
  - Kane, Florence Bayard, 1900
  - Kane, Francis Fisher, 1893
  - Lahn-Cabin passenger list, 1891 June 30
  - Laird, Warren P., 1892
  - Lambert, John, Jr., 1892, 1897
  - Lambert, Mary S., 1892
  - Lansdale, Maria, 1902
  - Masquelier, Jean, undated
  - McCall, Maria, undated
  - McCarthy, Anna C., 1891
  - McLean, Robert C., 1902
  - Middleton, L.L., 1897
  - Millard, Walter, 1884
  - Miscellaneous, 1868-1902
  - Molitor, John, 1902
  - Morgan, J.S., 1895
  - Morris, Sam, 1892
  - Moss, Mary, undated
  - Noland, Mary E., 1892, 1896
  - Noland, N.B., 1891-1892
  - Noland, William C., 1891-1902, undated
  - Parrish, Maxfield, 1897 February 25
  - Paterson, Mary M., 1889-1899
  - Paterson, Polly, 1890
  - Pennell, Elizabeth R., 1885
  - Photograph, undated
  - Pianelly, Norma, undated
  - Russell, Ella R., undated
  - Shields, Charles W., 1897
  - Simpson, Edith M., 1892
  - Simpson, H.C., 1891-1892
  - Smith, Esther F.W., undated
  - Smith, Marie, 1879
  - Squire, E.S., 1892
  - Squire, S.H., 1892
  - Sterwanee, F.C., 1889
  - Stewardson, J., 1892
  - Stewardson, John, 1882
  - Stokes, Ellen W., 1897
  - Sturt, W.N., 1893-1897
  - T Square Club, 1896
  - University Club, St. Louis, 1901
  - Whitall, J.W., 1875
  - Yarnall, Edward, 1892
- Series VIII. Kane Family Financial records, 1830-1952; Family bills, receipts, deeds, insurance policies from 1830-1952.
  Presented by Mrs. Joseph C. Aub, Dr. Oliver Cope, Thomas Pym Cope, and Mrs. Thomas P. Hazard, 1968-1974, children of Walter Cope and Eliza Middleton Kane Cope. Cope family material acquired from the Rhode Island Historical Society.
  Bills (financial).; Deeds.; Insurance policies.; Receipts.
  - John Kintzing Kane, 1830-1865
  - Robert Patterson Kane, 1846-1864
  - Francis Fisher Kane, 1929-1936
  - Eliza Middleton Kane Cope, 1904-1952
- Series IX. Kane Family Miscellany, 1793-1973; Architectural drawings, photographs, newspaper clippings, family biographies, pamphlets, address books, and notebooks from 1793-1973.
  Early American History note: An assortment of business and institutional records, which include information on insurance on vessels (1793-1809), a commonplace book (1834-1835), numerous receipt and account books, and subscriptions to support charitable work.
  Presented by Dr. Oliver Cope, 1967. Cope family material acquired from the Rhode Island Historical Society.
  See itemized inventory.
  Architectural drawings.; Biographies.; Business and Skilled Trades; Business Records and Accounts; Commonplace Book; Diaries.; Diplomas.; Haiti; Institutional Records; Notes.; Photograph albums; Social Life and Custom; Trade
  - John Kintzing Kane, 1793-1857
    - American Philosophical Society, 1835; No. 1; 5.0 vols.
      Subscription lists for the erection of an astronomical observatory.
    - Pennsylvania Literary Association of Philadelphia, 1842-1845; No. 2; 1.0 vol.
    - Commonplace book, 1831-1838; No. 3; 1.0 vol.
      Containing extracts from newspapers and copies of letters from various persons.
    - Philadelphia, 1824; No. 4; 1.0 vol.
      Subscription book for a civic ball in honor of Lafayette.
    - Leiper, Mary B., 1854-1855; No. 5; 1.0 vol.
      Receipt book.
    - Aykroyd, Henry, Undated; No. 6; 1.0 vol.
      Ledger (record of a butcher's sales).
    - Bolivar, George W., 1845-1850; No. 7; 1.0 vol.
    - Receipt book, Undated; No. 8; 1.0 vol.
    - Society for the promotion of legal knowledge and forensic eloquence, 1821 January 17-1822 March 13; No. 9; 1.0 vol.
    - Davis, Amos, 1849-1853; No. 10; 1.0 vol.
      Estate. Account.
    - Donaldson, John, 1793-1809; No. 12; 1.0 vol.
      Insurance of vessels, plus newspaper clippings of the visit of Kossuth.
    - Philadelphia Managers of the Consolidation Ball, 1854; No. 13; 3.0 vol.
    - List of ships which were insured, 1835; No. 11; 1.0 vol.
    - Bunker, Benjamin H., 1854-1857; No. 14; 1.0 vol.
    - Philadelphia Museum Company, 1827-1836; No. 15; 1.0 vol.
    - Philadelphia society for the Employment and Instruction of the Poor, Undated; No. 16
      Account book with the Girard Life Insurance Annuity and Trust Company.
    - Address, discourse, opinions, 1831-1849; Published works.
    - American Philosophical Society--Proceedings, 1854
    - Autobiography, 1795-1849; Typewritten.
    - Candid view of the Presidential Question, 1828; Published work.
      By a Pennsylvania [John K. Kane]
    - Cases examined, 1833; Handwritten notebook.
    - Hamlet, introduction to..., Undated; Handwritten. Oversize.
    - Letters of John Kintzing Kane and Jane Duval Leiper Kane, 1914; Published work.
    - Pamphlets, 1836, 1853
      Notes on some questions decided by the Board of Commissioners under the convention with France; Education of idiots--an appeal to the citizens of Philadelphia.
    - Photographs, Undated
    - Poems, Undated
    - Williamson, Passmore vs. John K. Kane, 1855-1857; Published works.
  - Francis Fisher Kane, 1857-1953
    - Address books, 1952-1953
    - Composition book, 1927
    - Family Biographies
      Primarily regarding Elisha Kent Kane.
    - Legal materials, 1942-1948
      Published pamphlets of the Molzahn case and other court cases, receipts of payments for the Pastor Kurt E.B. Molzahn defense fund.
    - Newspaper clippings, Bulk, 1898-1908; 1857-1946
      Scrapbook contains articles primarily concerning Francis Fisher Kane, some earlier dated clippings refer to Elisha Kent Kane. Also, contains envelope with news accounts of the Molzahn case.
    - Newspaper scrapbook, 1857-1908
    - Notebooks
      Box of ten notebooks primarily F.F. Kane's, with two cash books of Robert P. Kane.
    - Notes, Undated
    - Notes--Haiti and Santo Domingo, 1922
    - Philadelphia award, 1936 February 5
      Typewritten transcript of speechs and presentation of award to F.F. Kane.
    - Photograph album, 1886
      Princeton University scientific expedition, photographs of South Utah, Colorado, and North Carolina.
    - Photographs
    - Printed materials, 1900-1952
      Includes the monthly publications of the American Civil Liberties Union, the Pennsylvania Prison Society, some publications from the United Nations and the Philadelphia Award given to Kane in 1935.
    - Printed materials, Molzahn defense fund, 1942-1955
    - Scrolls, 1913-1952
      Diplomas, honorary degrees, and other honors.
  - Eliza Middleton Kane Cope, 1884-1973
    - Address book, diaries, 1884-1918
    - Album of Theatrical programs #1, 1914-1921
    - Album of Theatrical programs #2, 1909-1917
      Name on spine: Anne Francis Cope.
    - Architectural drawings, 1909
    - Cope, Oliver--Contributions to General Surgery, 1973
    - Cope, Thomas P.--Architectural drawings, 1933
    - Cope, Thomas P.--Blueprints, 1932
    - Kane, Florence B.--The Pilgrim Scrip, 1927
    - Journal of the Voyages of the Bark "Our Union"
      Commanded by Captain F. Miller.
    - Photograph album #1, 1875
      Travel photographs to Eliza M. Kane from her mother.
    - Photograph album #2, Undated
      Includes some family members: Eliza Middleton Kane, Oliver H. Middleton, Mrs. R. Izard Middleton, Lizzie Young (Fisher cousin), Aunt Bayard (Kane cousin).
    - Photograph album #3, Undated
      Album Parterre. Eighteen floral designs: twelve cabinet size, oval and dome. Six carte de visite for one, two, and three portraits interspersed with other leaves for four portraits. Contains portraits of famous actors, actresses, some hand-colored.
    - Photographs--box, Undated
      Black and white photographs and negatives of Cope children and grandchildren. Also, some cabinet card portrait photographs.
    - Photographs--oversize, Undated